Priyanka Saggu

About

Summary

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast, having experience working with highly distributed infrastructure on hybrid cloud platforms. During the internship at Atlan, I've been working on writing fully automated product releases, with zero interference on the client enterprise end. As a summer trainee at Dgplug, I have set up and managed multiple Linux-based servers. Wrote Infrastructure as Code(IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/servers. Have experience with On-Prem deployment environments using Rancher. And I'm an Outreachy'19 alum at GNOME Foundation too.

Personal Info

- Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com
- Website: https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/
- Gitlab-gnome: https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119
- Gitlab-salsa: https://salsa.debian.org/priyankasaggu119-guest
- **Github**: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/

Experience

- AtlanHQ
 - DevOps Engineer (May' 20 Present)
 - DevOps Engineer Intern (Feb' 20 May' 20)
- GNOME Foundation
 - Outreachy'19 Intern (Dec' 19 Mar' 20)
- Learn IT, Girl (Certificate)
 - Scholar mentee 2019
- GeeksforGeeks, Noida (Certificate)
 - Graphics designer intern 2018

Community Learning & Contributions

Dgplug Summer Training

2018-Present

- Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.
- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers, orchestrated using Docker Swarm, for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to lymworkbook a Vagrant lab environment in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.
- Setup OpenVpn service, creating both OpenVPN server and Certificate Authority (CA) server on different machines.
- Setup On-Prem multi-cluster orchestriation platform for microservices applications deployment using kubernetes tools.

Gnome - gtranslator

2019-Present

- Enhanced UI by revamping existing widgets in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines(HIG).
- Entirely redesigned the old search and replace bar dialog to a new sliding overlay style custom widget, using libdazzle library.

Debian

2019

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

Skills/ Keywords

- Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat family (CentOS)
- Scripting: Bash and utils, Python
- **Backend**: Python (Django)
- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)
- GUI Toolkit: GTK+ 3 in pure C
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite
- Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2
- Version control systems: Git
- **DevOps**: Kubernetes, Rancher, Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm, Helm/Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana, Velero, Weave Cloud, Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), RabbitMQ, Replicated/KOTS, CircleCI, Github Actions
- Misc: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), OpenCV, Java-J2SE

Education

B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonepat), Haryana 2015-2019

• AISSCE (12th-PCM)

Govt. Model Senior Secondary School, Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.) 2014-2015

• AISSE (10th)

S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School, Fatehabad, Haryana 2012-2013

Conferences/ Events

- 2019 PyCon, India
- 2019 DebUtsav, Delhi
- 2017 International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

Additional activities

- Regional Head Haryana, GirlScript Foundation Private Limited (2019-2020).
- Organised Python 101 BootCamp in Haryana state-level technical fest, Technova.

• Attended IWD'19 event in Google, Gurugram. Also, the women's mega day meetup in Microsoft, Gurugram.

Writings

Self

- Automating private dataproc cluster deployment having Presto Installation (on GCP)!
- Custom GCP type provider for automating VPC Network Peering creation!
- Parse Server On-Premise Deployment
- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Consul Key-Value Store!
- Let's get started with iptables!
- Automating WordPress Installation Through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production!

Publications

- Introduction to Xamarin | A Software for Mobile App Development and App Creation
- Flutter | An Introduction to the Open Source SDK by Google

References

• Chandan Kumar, OpenStack/RDO developer, Red Hat, chkumar AT redhat DOT com